Guide to the Robert L. Andersen papers,1962-2001.
Andersen, Robert L. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert L. Andersen papers, 1962-2001.
22-2-3580
Robert Louis, Andersen 1937-
32.4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Publications, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection contains correspondence, grant files, Horticultural Science Department planning documents (Geneva), McCarthy Farm Nursery documents, meetings and activities files, publications files, and New York plum pox virus files.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Emeritus of Horticulture, Department of Horticultural Sciences at Geneva, NY. Areas of expertise include plant breeding, sweet cherry genetics, plum breeding, apricot breeding, variety testing, rootstock testing, and adult education relating to deciduous tree fruit production. From 1985 to 1990 he served as Professor and Chairman of the Department of Horticultural Sciences at NYS Agricultural Experiment Station, Geneva, New York. He retired July 14, 2004.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection contains correspondence, grant files, Horticultural Science Department planning documents (Geneva), McCarthy Farm Nursery documents, meetings and activities files, publications files, and New York plum pox virus files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Andersen, Robert Louis,1937-; New York State Agricultural Experiment Station.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Study and teaching.; Horticulture--Study and teaching.; Sweet cherry--Rootstocks--Testing.; Sweet cherry--Varieties--Testing.; Plum--Rootstocks--Testing.; Plum--Varieties--Testing.; Apricot--Rootstocks--Testing.; Apricot--Varieties--Testing.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence A-Forsline, 1993-2004 (Box 1)
- Correspondence Frecon-Kraft of Canada, 1990-2004 (Box 2)
- Correspondence Lang-NY Cherry Growers Association, 1994-2001 (Box 3)
- Correspondence NY Fruit Consultants-R, 1990-2004 (Box 4)
- Correspondence S-Z, 1994-2003 (Box 5)
- International Correspondence A-I, 1993-2001 (Box 6)
- International Correspondence Italy-Ukraine, 1987-2002 (Box 7)
- Collaboration; Correspondence; Russia Collaboration, 1998-2002 (Box 8)
- Collaboration (cont.); Dave Weil; Research Collaboration Files, 1990-2000 (Box 9)
- Research Collaboration Files (cont.) 1988-2002; China Trip 1987-1993 (Box 10)
- China Trip (cont.) 1993-2000; Grants Files (partial); Cooperative Extension Files 1993-2000 (Box 11)
- Horticultural Science Department Planning Documents; Stone Fruit Breeding/Culture Program Planning Documents, 1994-2003 (Box 12)
- Planning Documents (cont.); NYSAES McCarthy Farm Nursery, Management by Robert L. Andersen (ca. 1992-1995), 1984-1998 (Box 13)
- NYSAES McCarthy Farm (cont.), 1991-1994 (Box 14)
- Chronological Files, 1992-1999 (Box 15)
- Chronological Files, 1999-2001 (Box 16)
- Chronological Files; RLA Symposium; NY Plum Pox Files, 1996-1999, 2002-2005 (Box 17)
- NY Plum Pox Virus; PPV Training; PPV Files, 2000-2001 (Box 18)
- Publications, 1974-1997 (Box 19)
- International Nursery, correspondence and agreements 1988-1993; Accessions, ideas for accessioning 1993-1999 (Box 20)
- Stone Fruit Dispersals 1994-1997; Back-up Files 1994-1998 (Box 21)
- Back-up Files (cont.) 1995-1998; Dispersal Notebooks (3); Ideas for Accessioning 1998-2001 (Box 22)
- Back-up Files (cont.) 1998-1999; NY Growers, correspondence 1995-2001 (Box 23)
- NY Growers, correspondence (cont.); Cornell Research Foundation; Stone Fruit and Pear Patents and Trademarks; Intellectual Property, 1997-2003 (Box 24)
- Accessions, back-up 1997-2002; Correspondence 1997 (Box 25)
- Accessions, backup, correspondence 2002-2003; USA Fruit Tree Nurseries, correspondence; Agreements and Catalogs 1993-1997; Tester's Club, IPM, Inc, variety (Box 26)
- IPM, CRF-Z, Correspondence 1995-2002; NC-140 1987-1997; Stone Fruit Root Stock; NY Back-up Files 1990-2006; Pear Progress Reports 1948-1977, 1948-1977, 1990-2006 (Box 27)
- NY Backup files (cont.) 2001-2004; Dispersals Book Logs; Stone Fruit Dispersals (Box 28)
- Stone Fruit Dispersals; Backup Files 2003-2004; Propagation Agreements 1994-2000; Dispersal Notebooks 1990-2005; Pear Cultivars and Culture 1992-2001 (Box 29)
- Pear Cultivars and Culture 1993-2000; Stone Fruit and Dispersals; Book Logs 1997-1998; Backup Files 1998-2000 (Box 30)
- USA Fruit Tree Nurseries, correspondence, agreements, and catalogs; A-Hilltop, 1994-2001 (Box 31)
- USA Fruit Tree Nurseries, correspondence, agreements, and catalogs; IPM, Inc.-A, 1995-2005 (Box 32)
- International Nurseries, correspondence, 1995-2004 (Box 33)
- Poster: Sharka(Plum Pox Disease) (Map-case Folder 1)